There's a guy on YouTube called Matt
Armstrong and he makes videos about
repairing
crash damage cars.
I've just bought the cheapest 911 GT3
in the world.
And today we're going to try
and rebuild it in 24
hours.
And I've been addicted to Matt's content,
not just because I like cars, but
Matt is a master storyteller
and anyone in the content creation space
should go and study his videos to the way
that he raises the stakes, has setups,
has very powerful introductions.
It's incredible.
However, there was a problem.
Through watching Matt's videos,
I watched him rebuild
an Audi RS6 and I had to buy an Audi RS6
and I've been
watching his videos ever since.
They get uploaded on a Sunday evening
and I'm the
first person to watch them. But there
was one car that he crash damage repaired
more than once, and I didn't realize it,
but at the time I was falling in love with
that car and that car
was a Porsche 911 GT3
and I had to buy one.
[upbeat music]
Now, for many of you watching this,
let me tell you this,
most of us live on the
hedonic treadmill, which means
that whatever success we experience, we
kind of just ignore,
and then we set another goalpost.
We say to ourselves, "Oh,
if I could just earn 5,000 more a month,
I'd be
so happy." "Oh,
if I could just get a few thousand more
followers, I'd
be so happy." And every single milestone
that I've got to in life,
I've got to the end and kind of thought,
"Is that it?" I remember thinking,
when I hit a million
followers, I'm going to be so happy.
I'm going to get all my friends together.
We're going to rent a private jet.
We're going to fly to Vegas.
The reality was you hit a million and
kind of feel nothing.
Same goes with revenue for a business.
You go, "It's amazing.
We're going to hit seven figures soon."
And the second you hit seven figures on
Stripe,
you don't feel anything.
So you say to yourself,
"Maybe it's 2 million, maybe it's
5 million, maybe it's 10 million."
And continually over time, sometimes you
think to yourself,
when am I going to be happy with the
progress that I've made?
And then you realize this
is a very common occurrence.
It's called the hedonic treadmill.
And although we like to convince ourselves
that if we just keep pushing and keep
working,
that maybe there'll be happiness at the
end of the tunnel, very often
there's not. And the crazy thing
that comes with that is
when you're making good
money and it's not making you happy,
you kind of feel worse than you would
if you weren't making good money and you
weren't very happy because you have so
much, yet it's not
really making an impact on a personal
level.
However, when I bought the RS6,
every single time I got in it through
every week and every
month after I bought it, it made me happy.
Every time I started the engine
and heard the exhaust crackle,
I was like, wow. There
are so many things
that you can get used to in life,
but for me personally,
having a nice car
was one I'd forgotten all about.
Every single year
in my 20s I drove either a Volkswagen Golf
or a Polo and I
didn't really care
that much about what I was
driving.
And the purpose of this video
is there'll be some of you out there kind
of probably
making the same excuses as me not to treat
yourself, whether it's a business class
flight, whether it's a nice car.
But honestly, I've come to
realize these are the best things
that you can waste your money on because
every
time you get in,
it kind of makes you think, oh,
do you know what this is worth
working for?
Because so much of the success metrics
that we have,
they're just numbers.
Followers, doesn't really mean anything.
Money, sure you can become less stressful,
but there's nothing really physical.
I then got nice watches,
but then I felt like a dickhead when I
was wearing them.
If I was wearing an AP right now,
you'd be like, dickhead. So I was like,
fuck it.
I'm not just going to buy my dream car.
I'm going to buy two of them.
You've not been in this properly before,
have you?
I've not.
What do you think?
I like it. You can feel every bump.
You can tell it's built for fucking speed.
Well, it gets better when you twist this.
[engine revving]
Fucking hell.
It's all right.
We're within the speed limit, guys.
Don't worry.
I had to get a manual as well.
The Audi RS6 is one of the best cars ever.
Any of you that are thinking of doing it,
get it.
I was never an Audi fanboy before,
but it's
so comfortable, so reliable.
It's just so good and in some ways it
still is the perfect car.
But the three issues
that I had with the RS6 was,
one, it's a bit quiet.
Although the V8 engine makes a nice
crackle
when you're starting
and you get like a nice cold start on it.
When you're punishing it,
it doesn't really give you the noise
that you want.
Sometimes you just want to hear a bit of-
[engine revving]
And I'm someone that doesn't really care
about going that fast.
I would say the majority of your fun
is had between second and third gear.
So the Audi, I was kind of like, oh,
do I get the exhaust then?
Do I straight pipe it?
Then the second thing with the Audi,
I really kind of wanted
an Alcantara steering wheel, which
is like the suede steering wheel,
and I was even
thinking maybe I go to Audi and I say,
"Oh,
can you change my steering wheel?" Then
the nail in the coffin
was taking it to the
track.
The Audi was so good on the track,
but going through corners, it just felt
really heavy and lumbersome and there
were Porsches there, there were
GT3s there, there
were Aston Martins there, Ferraris
and I was like,
I'm going to go have a look at a 911.
And I've never not bought a car
that I've gone to look at, this included.
Now before this seems like a video where
I'm showing off, I want to introduce a
concept called touching your future.
This is one for you, Deborah.
First time-
Pretty dumb. I just put all the money
that I had together, and
when I sat there in
business with no money left in my current
account, what I was doing was
experiencing what I could have in the
future if I was just willing to work hard,
pull some late nights,
put myself in uncomfortable positions.
Same with the RS6. When I bought the RS6,
I didn't really need it,
but I thought, "Do you know what?
This will be my first proper luxury car."
Then the same with the Porsche.
There's never going to be a time in your
life that
you can really afford one of these.
But I have a feeling
that sitting in this
and having this as my daily driver every
day will motivate me to do the things
that maybe some days I can't be arsed to
do.
Now, am I saying get yourself in debt?
Am I saying make stupid purchases?
I'm saying no. But I'm saying
if there's something you want to do
and you can still
survive if you do it,
you should 100% do it.
Smiles per miles is the most important
ratio here.
If I think about the things
that make me happy in life,
family,
partner, son, holidays, work.
When you're a dude,
there's just something you get from cars.
And there's a famous Jeremy Clarkson
quote, you're going to have to find this,
Declan, where he says
that you can have a relationship with a
car.
Definitely.
He's like, everyone thinks this
is just one and a half tons of metal,
glass and
plastic. But over time,
you can be in love with a car.
I think I'm going to be in love with this
one.
It's what non-car people don't get.
They see all cars as just a ton
and a half, two tons of
wires, glass, metal and rubber.
You can develop a relationship with a
car,
and that's what non-car people just don't
get.
I don't even go anywhere.
I probably won't even go to the track.
I'll probably get too scared.
I'll probably take the Audi again.
What is the track mode on that?
How does that compare to the sport mode?
So,
in essence,
when you put it into sport mode
or track mode, the track's going to
make the suspension even stiffer.
Okay.
There's another function called auto clip,
which means that when I change gears,
it revs to get a smoother transition.
Oh, yeah, I know that is. Yeah.
So-
Can't you do that manually as well?
In manual, you can heel and toe.
Yeah.
So as you're braking, you put your heel-
Yeah
... on the accelerator,
but this will do it for me.
Okay.
Yeah, sick.
And it just matches the revs.
Yeah. Cool.
So that's sick. Exhaust is open,
everything firms up.
Now,
the best thing I like about this car
is it revs to 9,000 RPM.
[sighs]
Which you don't get in any other models.
[engine accelerating]
And it starts at four, five,
six.
And the horsepower peaks at 8,700.
Okay.
So I'm going to see if I can get us-
All right
...
near 9,000 revs within the speed limit,
of course.
Sounds crazy, but every once in a while,
you should just do something that makes
you feel alive.
Yeah.
Even if it's just swimming in the sea.
In Australia, one of the things,
I always used to take the piss out of cold
water
therapy,
but then once a day I'd go swim in the
sea, middle of winter,
just because it makes you feel something.
And also,
I think it's quite important to maybe do
things that maybe your peers
want to do. And here's another thing.
Some people are going to watch this video
and hate it, hate me.
But there's a fine line between being
inspired
and being jealous.
I've been jealous of people before.
Adam Sullivan with the Lambos,
I've blocked him. I was jealous.
I worked through it.
We're good friends now.
But it's so important that
when you see people doing things
that you want to do,
that you're not bitter about it.
Because instead,
you could so easily use those
juices to just make yourself feel more
inspired. Anyone can do this.
Anyone.
And this is on finance.
I didn't buy it outright.
That'd be stupid.
Even if I drive it for a year,
trade it in, get bored of it, sell it.
[engine accelerating] All right.
9,000 revs.
[engine accelerating] Six. Seven.
It's there,
we're going to go to eight. But
it sounds so good.
[engine accelerating] Oh.
Now, the PDK gearbox
that you get with one of these in
automatic
is amazing. And there is part of me
[engine accelerating] that thinks,
"Oh, should I have got the PDK?"
But as I've been paddle shifting here,
I know that I'd just be thinking,
"Oh, I wish I had a clutch."
[engine accelerating]
Pros about this car. Actually,
let's start with the negatives.
Not that comfortable. No front cameras.
Cup two tires, very sticky,
so stones can get chucked up.
The other day I was going around a corner,
a stone came in through the window.
Expensive.
[brakes squeaking] And squeaky brakes,
which you usually get with performance
brakes. Positives, you feel everything.
The sound.
Oh, another negative, getting in and out.
When I first got in, I was like, "Mate,
how do I get out of this?" You had to show
me the proper way to get in and out of it.
What else? Positives.
It's just beautiful.
You just park this in your garage
and just look at it.
It feels, oh, it's just great.
And I'd say having manual
is a positive and a negative.
Positive, you get to drive manual.
Negative,
you have to drive manual.
You have any questions, man?
So the exhaust is on right now, yeah?
You can turn the exhaust off and on.
That's on normal.
Yeah.
Can you get on max exhaust?
Can we hear what that sounds like?
Well, it'll probably be the same as...
So there's sport exhaust.
It's pretty loud both sides.
[engine accelerating] Just let me make
sure there's
no popo.
It says there's one up here.
[engine accelerating] Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah, that's nice.
I've never had a rear-engine car before.
And then you can raise this thing
or lower it with the suspension, right,
as well?
Great point. Yeah, so there
is a front axle lift.
Okay.
Which raises the front by about four
inches.
But also the back of the car is very low.
So there's some diffusers on the back
under the exhaust.
And first time I took it in the drive,
I-
Bit of a scrape.
But I've just come to terms
that having a GT3, because
it's such a low car,
having the underneath scrape
is just going to be a normal part of
owning one.
And when I take this back-
You can replace it for-
Yeah. There's-
Reasonable cheap, right?
... like, a hundred tray. Yeah.
Yeah.
So I just have a feeling that
probably that front
diffuser, rear diffuser,
whenever I trade in they'll say, "Oh,
it's worth this
minus £5,000, maybe even £10,000,"
for that.
What about insurance for someone wanting
to buy it? Is the insurance limited?
So my insurance on this is £200 a month,
so like,
$400, which I don't think is crazy for...
How much is your insurance a month?
Oh, I've only got third party.
Do you?
Yeah.
God.
It's not worth it.
So yeah, the insurance isn't crazy.
I've got a pretty good
track record.
Oh,
here's another thing that's quite cool.
On this model, you get a track warranty.
So if I take this to the track,
because it's supposed to be a track car,
if I'm
ragging the engine and I blow the engine,
they'll replace it for free.
Oh, sick.
And I've still got an extended warranty on
the car, which you
can't get wear and tear,
but
if something goes wrong, if
that front axle lift stops working,
it's Porsche's
problem. Right.
So who would you say this car is for,
and who's it not for?
Who's it for?
Yeah, who's it for?
You'll know. Because there
are some people out there, right.
Let's say you have a budget of,
let's say the second you can afford car
repayments of £2,000 a month, $4,000 a
month.
But in Australia it's so much worse.
One of these secondhand
is more expensive than a brand new one in
the UK because of
luxury car tax.
Wow.
But once you can afford, I don't know,
yeah, 2K, 4K a month,
a lot of people think Lambo.
And I do love a Lambo, an SVJ,
an Aventador.
I've driven them.
But to me, when I think fuck you money,
I think
Porsche. And I think that
if I could afford it,
I probably even would've got the GT3 RS.
Maybe, I don't know. I just-
What's the difference between the RS
and the normal one?
GT3 RS, first of all, you'll see there's,
like, four stalks on the steering wheel
because you control the spoiler
and the diffuser and stuff.
Oh, wow.
A massive wing on the back
and loads of aero on it that just makes it
look even sicker.
But one of those here is $800,000.
That's insane.
Yeah.
Which is £400,000 for a Porsche, which
is just nuts.
But if I had the money,
would I consider it? Maybe.
I actually think in some respects the GT3
can look better,
but that's maybe what someone
that couldn't afford a GT3 RS would say.
I've got to ask myself,
did I pick this car
over that because I truly find it more
beautiful?
Obviously,
because I couldn't afford the other one.
This video is a little bit different to
some of the ones that we usually do.
But I just thought I couldn't have
a milestone in my life without sharing it
with you.
Why? Because it's fucking cool.
If you don't like seeing me win,
then you can
fuck off and watch someone else's views.
I'm pretty sure YouTube
is going to recommend a video to put here,
one of mine that
isn't about showing off about a new car.
I'm sure you'll enjoy it,
so why don't you watch that?